(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-22T16:57:19.966020",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
うわー！はい！
Whoa! Yes!
外国旅行ときめいたのがみたいな感じでいくかと思いきや
I thought it'd be like traveling abroad and getting all excited,
始まったばかりです！みんな盛り上がってるかー！と始まったばかりです。
but it just started! Everyone hyped up? It just started.
えっと、あのハッシュタグ「#ノエル生誕はっぴーLIVE」で
Um, with the hashtag #NoelBirthdayHappyLIVE,
今日は1時間いっぱいつぶやいてください！
please tweet as much as you want for an hour today!
今回はね、なんと久しぶりのバラエティパートもあります！
This time, amazingly, we also have a long-awaited variety segment!
バラエティパートとそのあとにライブパートがあるのでぜひぜひ盛り上がってくださーい！
There's a variety segment and then a live segment, so please get super hyped!
じゃあちょっとね、だんちょうバラエティパートの準備があるんで、さっそく準備して
Well, Danchou has to get ready for the variety segment, so I'll go prepare right away!
行きたいと思います！いっぱいスクショ撮ったりね、あの感想とかいっぱい呟いてね！
Take lots of screenshots and tweet your thoughts!
ということで準備してきまーす！おまー！
So I'll go get ready! Bye!
真の牛丼女王は誰だ！？第1回ホロライブ牛丼女王決定戦！
Who is the true Gyudon Queen?! The 1st Hololive Gyudon Queen Showdown!
うおー！いぇーい！
Woah! Yay!
はい、ということでまずはこの大会の絶対王者をご紹介しましょう！
Now then, first let's introduce the absolute champion of this tournament!
牛丼を愛して300年！朝はおろしポン酢牛丼、昼はチーズ牛丼、夜は通常牛丼！
Loving gyudon for 300 years! Grated ponzu gyudon in the morning, cheese gyudon at noon, normal gyudon at night!
1日3食牛丼もドンと来い！「ホロライブいち牛丼を愛している！」
Bring on gyudon three meals a day! Proclaiming, "I love gyudon more than anyone in Hololive!"
と豪語する白銀ノエル様！
Shirogane Noel-sama!
いぇーい！白銀ノエルです！
Yay! It's Shirogane Noel!
いやもう牛丼好きっていったら団長っしょ！ということで絶対に負けません！今日は美味しく食べてまいります！
I mean, when it comes to gyudon lovers, it's gotta be Danchou! So I definitely won't lose! I'll enjoy eating it today!
うおおー！
Woah!
そして挑戦者はこのお方！
And our challenger is this person!
最近牛丼を食べたのは半年前！
The last time she ate gyudon was half a year ago!
今日は団長から牛丼の真髄を学びに来た！
Today she came to learn the true essence of gyudon from Danchou!
肉より野菜派！風真いろはだ！
Team vegetables over meat, Kazama Iroha!
いえーい！お肉食べるの久しぶりでござる。
Yay! It's been a while since I ate meat.
あ、今日の朝ご飯はキュウリをかじってきました！よろしくお願いします！
Ah, for breakfast today I just gnawed on a cucumber! Pleased to meet you!
キュウリだけじゃおなかふくらまないぞ！肉食え！肉食え！肉食え！
A cucumber won't fill your stomach! Eat meat! Eat meat! Eat meat!
はい、そしてね司会進行はこのわたくし、癒月ちょこが務めさせていただいております！癒月ちょこが務めさせていただきます！
Yes, and as for the MC, yours truly, Yuzuki Choco, is in charge! Yuzuki Choco is in charge!
この大会では一般的な牛丼、1,000円超えの高級牛丼、ちょこの愛情たっぷり手作り牛丼の3種類をご用意させていただいております！
In this tournament, we have prepared three kinds of gyudon: regular gyudon, luxury gyudon over 1,000 yen, and Choco's handmade gyudon full of love!
やったー！やったー！
Yay! Yay!
まずはね見た目を確認していただきつつ、そのあとはね試食をしてそれぞれをね当てていただくというとてもねシンプルかつ簡単な勝負となっております！
First, you'll check the appearance, and then you'll taste-test and guess which is which in a very simple and easy competition!
さっそく始めていきましょう！はい！はい！
Let's get started right away! Yes! Yes!
はい、ということでお二人の目の前に3種類の牛丼がご用意されました！
Yes, so three types of gyudon have been prepared in front of both of you!
うわー！牛丼だー！牛丼だー！
Woah! Gyudon! Gyudon!
まずはね、右側の牛丼いかがでしょうか？
First, what do you think of the gyudon on the right?
いやこれなんか、いつものおなじみみな感じがしますよ！もう見た目からして！匂いも、なんか、いつも馴染んでいる牛丼な気がしますね！
Well, this feels kinda like the usual familiar one! Just from the look of it! And the smell feels like the gyudon we're always used to!
あら、いろはも潜ります？
Oh, are you diving in too, Iroha?
おかえーま、牛丼見るのが
It's been so long since I last saw gyudon,
本当に久しぶりすぎて…
it's been ages...
全部確かに違うけど、どれがいつもある牛丼って言っても過言でござるな
They're all different, but any of them could be gyudon we've always seen.
そしたら真ん中のほうの牛丼はいかがでしょうか？
Then how about the gyudon in the middle?
真ん中も…
The middle...
いやでも、こちらはあれなんですね。玉ねぎが、はい、細かいですね。玉ねぎが。
But wait, this one... the onions are, yeah, quite fine. The onions.
そう、牛丼って結構玉ねぎがちょっと大きめに切られてること多いんですけど
Right, gyudon usually has rather large-cut onions,
これはちょっと細かいということ。そして、肉が多い。
but this one is finely cut. And there's a lot of meat.
つまり、あ、あ、ビビビビ、あ、分かりました。これ、あ、なるほど、なるほど、なるほどね。あ、お肉を売りにしてその分値段もみたいな感じなのかな？
Meaning—ah, I see! So it's a place that prides itself on meat, and the price reflects that?
しかもチョコあの玉ねぎ嫌いなんで、あ、はい。
Plus, Choco hates onions, so—ah, right.
あ、玉ねぎ嫌いだから…ないのこれ、玉ねぎないのほとんど。ないの？
Ah, she hates onions... so this has almost no onions? None?
はいはいはいはい。はいはいはいはいはい。なるほど。
Right, right, right. I see.
そしたらね、一番左側のほうの牛丼はいかがでしょうか？
Then, how about the gyudon on the far left?
左側、あ、え、待って、これ玉ねぎいっぱいある。え、いっぱい入ってる。さっきのチョコ戦の理論からいうと、こっちが…
The left side... ah, wait, this has lots of onions. Based on Choco's theory, this is...
となるとですよ。におい、嗅いでもいいですかね？あ、でも確かに、におい嗅ぎたい。嗅いでください。嗅いでください。
In that case... Can I smell it? Ah, I definitely want to smell it. Please do.
うんうんうんうんうん。え、おいしそう。
Mmm-mmm. Ah, it looks delicious.
待って、え、おなか空いてきた。ちょっと、あ、ちょっ、チョコのにおいも嗅いでもいいよ？
Wait, I'm getting hungry. Hold on—Choco, can I smell yours too?
あ、チョコ先生のも。ちょっと…あ、でもね、ちょっと手前に…あるんで、ちょっと一杯…
Choco-sensei's too. Wait—ah, there's one right in front of us, so maybe just one cup...
え、いいですか？や、やった！おいしそう！このジョッキめちゃめちゃおしゃれ！なんか見覚えがある人もいると思うんだけど、これ弾丸チョウがデアンドル衣装でねよく飲んでいる…
Eh, is it okay? Yay! This mug is super stylish! Some might recognize it as the mug Danchou often drinks from in her Deandru outfit...
ジョッキなんですけど、え、でもいいんですか？一杯。いいですよ？じゃ、ちょっと、におい嗅ぎたい。
...but wait, is it okay? One glass. It's okay? Well then, I want to smell it.
え、いいですか？一杯。一応、お、ちょ,ちょ,におい,おい！なるほど！っていうことね！お！においだけで優勝！
Eh, is it okay? One glass. Just in case—wait, the smell—oh! I see! Wow, just the smell makes it a winner!
もう優勝…！いや、待て待て、飲む前に飲んじゃって大丈夫ですか？ノエル様。いや、むしろ、なんだろう、ケーキ付けの一杯だから全然…
Already a winner...! Wait, is it okay to drink before the tasting, Noel-sama? No, it's fine, since it's like pairing with cake...
まあね、余裕やわ。まあ、それではね、試食なんですが…
Well, piece of cake. Now then, for the tasting...
はい。ちょっとね目隠しをして食べていただこうと思います。
Right. We'll have you eat it blindfolded.
そうして見た目じゃわかんない、本当口でね。いや。うん。お。
That way you can't tell by looks, you have to use your mouth. Yeah. Oh.
よいしょ。じゃあちょっと団長、あい、なにも見えん！なにも見えんねえ！え、本当に見えなさそう…！
Here we go. So Danchou—I can't see anything! I really can't see anything!
真っ黒やで。いろは様も、はい、つけていただいて。え、大丈夫かなこれ？
It's pitch black. Iroha-sama, please put yours on too. Is this okay?
あ、本当だ、何も見えない。じゃあ、前のほうに…はい。はい！かわいい！ちょっと、どこだ！いろいろどこだ！
Ah, really, I can't see anything. Well then, forward... yes! Cute! Wait, where is it?!
はい、それではね、1つめのほうを食べさせていただきましょう。いただきます。いただきます。いただきます。
Right, then let's have you eat the first one. Itadakimasu. Itadakimasu. Itadakimasu.
いただきます。いただきますね。あらあらどうです？まあそんな大きな口を開けて…！
Itadakimasu. Enjoy. Oh my, how's that? Opening such a big mouth...!
おいしいんですけど、ちょっと、団長、牛丼食べるときに、いつもかけてるマストアイテムがありまして。
It's delicious, but Danchou, whenever you eat gyudon, you always have a must-have item.
あら、なにかしら？もしかして、ゆず七味なんですけど、ただ目隠ししてるから…確かにちょっと巻き散らしそう。
Oh, what could it be? Could it be yuzu shichimi? But since you're blindfolded... you might scatter it.
ettunanika... nanka, nanka...
Um, sort of... somehow...
ちょっとね、ごらん、ごらんなさい、チョコがあげてあげるぐらいだから。すいませんすいません。そうだったそうだった。
Look, since Choco is feeding you. Sorry, sorry. That's right, that's right.
よし、この見えないとこで、テッテーが行われている。かかってる？かかってるかな？
Okay, in this place where you can't see, teete is happening. Is it on? Is it on?
はい、めちゃめちゃいっぱいかかってるね。違う、罰ゲームみたいになってるから。
Yes, it's piled on heaps. No, it's turning into a penalty game.
じゃあちょっと、いただきます。あ、やっぱゆず七味の匂いが爽やか。
Well then, itadakimasu. Ah, the scent of yuzu shichimi is so refreshing.
いろは様はどう？うん、うん、うん、おいしい？
How about you, Iroha-sama? Mmm, mmm, mmm, is it delicious?
お味どんな感じ？甘い？しょっぱい？え、なんだろう、でもしょっぱくは、甘、甘たれみたいな味の汁でございます。
How does it taste? Sweet? Salty? It's a sauce flavor like sweet tare.
団長もさっきまで甘くておいしかったんすけど、すごく辛いす。
Danchou, up until just now it was sweet and delicious, but it's super spicy!
え、めっちゃおいしい！お肉ってこんなにおいしかったんでござるな。そうよ。
Super delicious! Meat was this delicious? Indeed.
はい、それではね、次の牛丼に移っていきましょうか。
Alright then, let's move on to the next gyudon.
はい、それではお二人方とも、2杯目よろしくお願いします！
Yes, then both of you, for the second bowl, please!
どちらかというと、さっぱり系？さっぱり系？
If anything, a refreshing type? Refreshing type?
あ、そんな、そんな、大きな大きなお口で、かき込んで！お肉いっぱいね！柔らかい？
With such a big, big mouth, shoveling it in! Lots of meat! Tender?
え、待って、玉ねぎ入ってるこっち？玉ねぎ、玉ねぎいるかいないかさっきより…
Wait, does this one have onions? Onions, are there onions or not compared to earlier...
四角でわかるのが、え、こっち、玉ねぎだった気がするでござるな。あ、本当？
You can tell by the shape—this one, I feel like it was onions. Oh, really?
ねぇ？
Hey?
ちなみにね、今持ってる風間様のね、あのスプーン、お肉が1つも乗っていません。
By the way, the spoon you're holding right now... doesn't have a single piece of meat on it!
え？え？見えないもの。
Eh? Eh? I can't see anything.
えっ…うそ、これごはん…？
Huh... No way, is this just rice...?
しょうがないわね、ちょっと貸しなさい。
It can't be helped. Let me borrow it for a second.
ありがとうございます。え、こ、ごはん？ うん、ごはんだけ。
Thank you very much. Eh, is this... rice? Yeah, just rice.
え？ ごはんだけなのよ、風間殿の。
Eh? It's just rice, Kazama-dono's!
いや、やはり…やはり肉が避けていくのが風間殿のこと。
No, as expected... meat just seems to avoid Kazama-dono...
おかしい。あ、え、あ、お肉置いてあげて？ あ、い,あ、うん、おいしい？
That's strange. Ah, um, ah, put some meat on for her? Ah, y-ah, um, um, is it good?
うん、うん。んーん。
Mm-hmm. Mmm-mmm.
牛丼はうまえよな。なんだろう？
Gyudon is delicious, huh? I wonder what it is?
しょ、生姜みたいな匂いする。
It smells like ginger.
生姜？ 分かる。生姜効いてる。
Ginger? I can tell. Ginger's flavor is strong.
ノエルさんもう半分以上食べてるんだけど、やばいって。
Noel-san's already eaten over half of it, that's crazy.
お肉の、なんだろう…こう、ホースを感じる。肉のホースを感じるから、
The meat's... I wonder... you can feel the broth. Because you can feel the meat's broth,
みなくとも食べれる。
even without looking, you can eat it.
あ、今食べてるのは白米だけですけどね。
Ah, what I'm eating right now is just white rice, though.
強すぎる。
She's too strong.
はい、それではね、そろそろ3杯目のほう…ディッシュしていきましょう！
Alright, then, it's about time we dish up the third bowl...!
三色丼ディッシュスタート！戻ってきまーす。
Three-color bowl dish start! Heading back.
あい、匂いする。匂い、いい匂いする。甘めの匂いがするね。
Smells good. Smells, smells good. It has a sweet aroma.
おっと、反応が今までのとちょっと違うぞ。
Whoa, the reaction is a bit different from the previous ones.
おっと、うーん。
Whoa, mmm.
どうですか、ノエル様。美味しい？
How is it, Noel-sama? Delicious?
うまい。めちゃ味が染みてる。うん、染みてる？
Delicious. The flavor soaked in so much. Yeah, soaked in?
染み渡ってるな。風間殿のは？
It's soaking right through. How about Kazama-dono's?
え、美味しい。なんか、タマネギとお肉…ちゃんと両方の味がする。
Eh, delicious. Somehow... onion and meat, you can taste both properly.
タマネギ…が、なんかね、甘い。
The onion... is, somehow, sweet.
ええ！？そうなの、そうなの？ そう、甘さを感じるな。
Eh?! Is that right, is that right? Yeah, you can feel the sweetness.
どう？どう？甘い？ 甘い！甘いです。今までより一番甘い？ 一番甘い。そう、甘さを感じるね。めっちゃ甘くて…味します。
How is it? How is it? Sweet? Sweet! It's sweet. Sweeter than before? The sweetest. Yeah, you can feel the sweetness. It's super sweet... you can taste it.
最後なんかめちゃめちゃ高評価ね。
The last one got remarkably high praise, huh.
はい、そしたらね、皆様、後ろを向いていただいて。
Alright then, everyone, please turn around.
いいですか、目隠しの方、お取りください。
Ready? Please take off your blindfolds.
ああ、世界が明るい！あがれ、あがれ！まぶし！まぶし！
Ah, the world is bright! Lift it up, lift it up! Bright! Bright!
ノエル先輩、どうやって食べたの？ぜんぶ食べてる。
Noel-senpai, how did you eat it? You ate all of them.
ご回答のご記入、よろしくお願いします！
Please write down your answers!
ま、ノエル様はね、簡単でしょ。
Well, for Noel-sama, it's easy, right?
え、風間殿、悩んでるのかな？
Eh, is Kazama-dono hesitating?
おっともうノエル様は余裕だな。あ、な？もう肉の中が答えを知ってるからね、もう。
Whoa, Noel-sama is already at ease. Ah, right? Because the meat itself already knows the answer.
それではね、回答を見てみましょうか。
Well then, let's take a look at the answers.
ノエル様の回答を、どどん！はい、これです。
Noel-sama's answer, ta-da! Yes, this is it.
あ、じゃあちょっと読み上げてもらってもいいですか？ 一番最初に食べたAが高級牛丼。で、次が一般的牛丼で、最後に食べたのがちょこ先セブン？
Ah, then could you read it out for me? The first one I ate, A, was high-end gyudon. Then next was standard gyudon, and the last one I ate was Choco-sensei 7?
え、理由はですね、まず最初の牛丼なんですけど、味がね、だんじょ…あのやっぱいろいろな
The reason is, for the first gyudon, the flavor... um, as expected, various ones,
特に一般的牛丼はもう何でも食べ続けてて思うんですけど、
especially standard gyudon, having eaten it constantly I think,
あの、甘めの牛丼もあるんですよ。
Um, there are sweet gyudon bowls too.
でも、多分今回色味からして、たぶん一般的な牛丼は、あ、あそこだなと思ったんですよね。
But this time, judging by the color, I thought the standard gyudon was right over there.
とあるところで、そこは甘くないんですよ。甘めす、甘め？
At a certain place, and it's not sweet there. Sweet... sweet?
ええ、そこまでに把握済み。やっぱ色味でわかる。色味でちょっと、あの濃い茶色とかだと結構味が付けられてるんだけど、
I had figured that much out. I can tell by the color. With darker brown, it's pretty heavily seasoned, but
やっぱね、あのちょっと味が、なんだろう、白っぽいというか、その…それは、あのあっさりとしてて、何杯でもいけるぞっていう、
you know, the flavor is a bit, how to put it, whitish... like, it's light and you can go for as many bowls as you want, that kind of
感じの、で、なったときに、
feel. So when that happened,
Aは味が濃かったんですよ。
A had a strong flavor.
お肉が結構ね、なんかく、とろける感じ？
The meat felt pretty... melting, sort of?
脂身とかもね、
And the fat too,
っていう感じがしたんで高級牛丼。でもここはね、まだわかんなかった。
that's why I thought it was high-end gyudon. But here, I still didn't know.
色味的にも濃いのが2種類あったから。で、Bが食べた瞬間に、あ、いつもの！って思いました。
Because there were two dark-colored ones. And with B, the moment I ate it, I thought, Ah, it's the usual!
あ、なるほど、すごい！
Ah, I see, amazing!
なんかお肉のね、感じした。あの舌ざわりとか、
Somehow I felt the meat's texture. The mouthfeel and
最後の…
the last...
やさしい。特に一番味が濃かったこれは、
It's gentle. Especially the one with the strongest flavor,
多分それぐらい愛情が込められてるんじゃないかなっていう
I feel like it was made with that much affection.
ああ、なるほどね！
Ah, I see!
あとタマネギがすごいなんか煮込まれてる感じ。
And the onions feel like they're really well-simmered.
ちょこ先生あんま好きじゃないって言ったけど、ちょこ先生は自分のために料理をするんではなく、我々のために料理をしてくれたから
Choco-sensei said she didn't like them much, but she didn't cook for herself; she cooked for all of us.
確かに！ね？あのタマネギ、ね？野菜を、野菜をね？
That's right! Right? Those onions, right? The vegetables, right?
ちゃんとこで、だからタマネギ多めでしかも優しくね、煮込んでみたいな感じで。
Plenty of onions, simmered gently like that.
確かに。
That's true.
では、いろは様の回答を見ていきましょう！
Now, let's look at Iroha-sama's answer!
はい、どうぞ！
Yes, go ahead!
はい、実は
Yes, actually
一緒なの！
they're the same!
でもめっちゃ迷った。完璧。
But I was so lost. Perfect.
でも、正直めっちゃ迷った。特にAとCですごく迷って。なるほどね。
But honestly, I was super lost. Especially between A and C. I see.
え、このAは、まず美味しいってなって、なんか食べたことない美味しさを感じて。
Uh, this A first tasted delicious, and I felt a deliciousness I'd never tasted before.
で、Bは、なんか食べてるうちにやっと食べ方ちょっと慣れてきて、あ、これなんか半年前ぐらいに…
And B, as I was eating it, I finally got used to how to eat it, and, ah, this is like half a year ago...
そう、よね。そう、だってこの感じはひょっとしたら半年前ぐらいに何か経験したことあるかもしれないと思って
Right. Right, because this feeling makes me think maybe I experienced something like this about half a year ago.
で、Cは、なんか本当に、めっちゃ甘くて、美味しかったんでございますって。AとCがどっちだろうってすごく迷っちゃって。
And C is, like, truly super sweet and delicious. I got so confused whether it was A or C.
でも比べたときにずっと食べてたのはCだからCがちょこ先生のなと思って。
But when comparing, the one I kept eating was C, so I thought C is Choco-sensei's.
判定権はづっと食べていたいかどうかのだった。
The judging criterion was whether I wanted to keep eating it.
牛丼はそれくらいさ、なんかね、あれなんですよ。あんまり食べたことない人でも、なんか味が分かりやすくね。
Gyudon is, you know, something like that. Even for people who haven't eaten it much, the flavor is easy to understand.
もうとにかく一品食ですね。
Anyway, it's a staple dish.
そう。あの、普通に日本の、まあ文化的な、あ、ちょっといいこと言いたいんですけど、全然語彙力がないんですけど。
Right. Um, normally Japanese, well, cultural, ah, I want to say something nice, but I have zero vocabulary.
まあ、牛丼はとにかくね、日常食なんで。
Well, gyudon is daily food anyway.
はい。もう完璧です。いえ、でもこれなら毎日食べれると、毎日牛丼は本当に毎日食べれる。
Yes. It's already perfect. Well, but if it's this, I can eat it every day, everyday gyudon really everyday I can eat.
ガチで美味しかった。
It was seriously delicious.
え、嬉しい！
Eh, I'm happy!
牛丼長者様、あの毎晩さ、こう、毎食か、毎食食べれ るっていうの分かったでしょ？味全然違うもんね。全然違う。
Gyudon tycoon-san, you understood that you can eat this every night, like every meal, right? The tastes are completely different. Completely different.
牛丼だけでも味違うんだよ。
Even just gyudon has different tastes.
これを見て挑戦したいと思ったホロメンはいるのか、どうか！
I wonder if there are any Holomembers who watched this and wanted to try it!
以上、第1回ホロライブ牛丼女王決定戦でした！
That concludes the 1st Hololive Gyudon Queen Deciding Match!
いやあ、めっちゃ美味しかった！
Man, it was super delicious!
いやあ、ちなみにみんな忘れてるかもしれないけど、これ生誕祭のライブです！このあとね、ライブパートもあるので、いっぱい食べたのでいっぱい歌って踊ります！
Man, by the way, you guys might have forgotten, but this is a birthday live! There's a live part coming up after this, so since I ate a lot, I'll sing and dance a lot!
ありがとうございました！ありがとうございました！ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much! Thank you very much! Thank you very much!
背は高い方がいい個がいいけど そんなタイプじゃなかったの
Though someone tall would be nice, that wasn't my type at all.
気難しそうな感じ どっちかっていうと苦手だったかな
He seemed hard to approach... if anything, I wasn't good with his type.
話すと全然違ってて 笑うと目が子供みたいで
Talking to him showed a whole different side, and when he laughed, his eyes looked like a child's.
クシャクシャになっちゃう目元 なんかすごいドキッとしたりして
The crinkling around his eyes made my heart skip a beat.
でも なんてホンモノのこと言っちゃうバカなの?
But... why did he have to go and say the real thing, what an idiot?
最初は「彼女いないよ」って ウソつくのが礼儀でしょ普通
At first, lying and saying "I don't have a girlfriend" is just common courtesy, right?
そうよ なんてこんなフラれた気分なの?
That's right... why do I feel like I've been rejected?
夢見る前から叶わない 恋って気付いちゃってんじゃない
Before even dreaming of it, I've realized this is a love that can't come true.
大好きになった どうしよう まだ出会ったばかりなんだけど
I've fallen so much in love... what should I do, even though we just met?
切ない気持ちが溢れてきて 胸がキュンとなってるよ
A painful feeling overflows, and my heart is tightening up.
そうよ 大好きなんだ どうもこうも すごいことになってきたよ
That's right... I love him so much... somehow things have gotten incredible.
会いたい気持ちで頭の中 ふわふわってなってるよ
My head is all fluffy with the desire to see him.
手をつないで離さないで 見つめ合って抱きしめ合って
Holding hands and never letting go, gazing at each other, hugging tightly,
「いい天気だね」
"Nice weather today,"
君が言うから
you say.
「本当だね」と答える 今日の空のこと
"It sure is," I reply with a smile.
話題にしたら心がふっと近くなる
If we talk about the sky today,
歩道を歩く 所々で水たまりが邪魔する
our hearts draw a little closer.
君と手を繋いで飛び越えてみるの
Walking along the pavement, puddles block our way,
太陽の光が舞う
so I hold your hand and we jump right over them.
次の季節が香り始める
Sunlight dances all around us.
その変化に抗うように
The next season begins to bloom.
「暑かった日々を忘れないで」と
Fighting against that changing tide,
最後の力振り絞って照らす
putting in one final push to shine bright,
空は見上げるたびそっと
telling us not to forget the hot days.
色や模様を着せ替えていって
Every time I look up, the sky softly
それはもう僕らの毎日のようなもんだね
changes its colors and patterns,
繰り返さないからこそもっと
just like our ordinary everyday life.
この日この時この瞬間
Because it never repeats, even more so,
思い上らずに刻みつけていたいよ
this day, this time, this exact moment,
宇宙まですぐ届く高さで泳いでいる魚たち
I want to engrave it in my heart forever.
そういえば昨日は茜色の空どこに潜ってたんだろ?
Fish swimming at a height that reaches the cosmos—
激しい雨にも耐えれない木の葉
come to think of it, where were they hiding yesterday in the madder-red sky?
へっちゃらな顔で伝えているんだ
Tree leaves that couldn't weather the heavy rain
やりきれないと逃げ出すことで救われるくらいなら
tell us with a carefree expression.
そんな未来は要らない
If we're saved by running away from what we can't handle,
今日 も誰が 空 の 下
we don't need a future like that.
泣いて 笑って 悔しがって
Today, someone, somewhere under the sky,
恋したり落ち込んだりして暮らしている
is crying, laughing, feeling regret,
満たされない何かがあって得られる喜びがあると思う
falling in love, feeling down, and living their life.
少なくとも、今の僕はそうだよ
I believe there is joy born from what leaves us unsatisfied.
君が僕の方を振り返って
At least, that's how I feel right now.
その思惑がたまらなくて
You look back at me,
幸せはいつもそうやって傍にいる
and that look in your eyes is so irresistible.
移り変わっていく空の下僕らいつまでもこの瞬間抱きしめながら
Happiness is always right by our side like that.
ふたり 歩いていこう
Under the ever-changing sky, holding this moment close,
「いい天気だね」
let's keep walking together.
君が言うから「本当だね」と答える
"Nice weather today,"
今日の空のこと話題にしたら心がふっと近くなる
you say, and I reply, "It sure is."
歩道を歩く 所々で水たまりが邪魔する
Talking about the sky today brings our hearts a little closer.
君と手を繋いで飛び越えてみるの
Walking along the pavement, puddles block our way,
太陽の光が舞う
so I hold your hand and we jump right over them.
次の季節が香り始める
Sunlight dances all around us.
その変化に抗うように
The next season begins to bloom.
「暑かった日々を忘れないで」と
Fighting against that changing tide,
最後の力振り絞って照らす
putting in one final push to shine bright,
空は見上げるたびそっと
telling us not to forget the hot days.
色や模様を着せ替えていって
Every time I look up, the sky softly
それはもう僕らの毎日のようなもんだね
changes its colors and patterns,
繰り返さないからこそもっと
just like our ordinary everyday life.
この日この時この瞬間
Because it never repeats, even more so,
思い上らずに刻みつけていたいよ
this day, this time, this exact moment,
宇宙まですぐ届く高さで泳いでいる魚たち
I want to engrave it in my heart forever.
そういえば昨日は茜色の空どこ에潜ってたんだろ?
Fish swimming at a height that reaches the cosmos—
激しい雨にも耐えれない木の葉
come to think of it, where were they hiding yesterday in the madder-red sky?
へっちゃらな顔で伝えているんだ
Tree leaves that couldn't weather the heavy rain
やりきれないと逃げ出すことで救われるくらいなら
tell us with a carefree expression.
そんな未来は要らない
If we're saved by running away from what we can't handle,
今日 も誰が 空 の 下
we don't need a future like that.
泣いて 笑って 悔しがって
Today, someone, somewhere under the sky,
恋したり落ち込んだりして暮らしている
is crying, laughing, feeling regret,
満たされない何かがあって得られる喜びがあると思う
falling in love, feeling down, and living their life.
少なくとも、今の僕はそうだよ
I believe there is joy born from what leaves us unsatisfied.
君が僕の方を振り返って
At least, that's how I feel right now.
その思惑がたまらなくて
You look back at me,
幸せはいつもそうやって傍にいる
and that look in your eyes is so irresistible.
移り変わっていく空の下僕らいつまでもこの瞬間抱きしめながら
Happiness is always right by our side like that.
ふたり 歩いていこう
Under the ever-changing sky, holding this moment close,
「いい天気だね」
let's keep walking together.
君が言うから「本当だね」と答える
"Nice weather today,"
今日の空のこと話題にしたら心がふっと近くなる
you say, and I reply, "It sure is."
歩道を歩く 所々で水たまりが邪魔する
Talking about the sky today brings our hearts a little closer.
君と手を繋いで飛び越えてみるの
Walking along the pavement, puddles block our way,
太陽の光が舞う
so I hold your hand and we jump right over them.
次の季節が香り始める
Sunlight dances all around us.
その変化に抗うように
The next season begins to bloom.
「暑かった日々を忘れないで」と
Fighting against that changing tide,
最後の力振り絞って照らす
putting in one final push to shine bright,
空は見上げるたびそっと
telling us not to forget the hot days.
色や模様を着せ替えていって
Every time I look up, the sky softly
それはもう僕らの毎日のようなもんだね
changes its colors and patterns,
繰り返さないからこそもっと
just like our ordinary everyday life.
この日この時この瞬間
Because it never repeats, even more so,
思い上らずに刻みつけていたいよ
this day, this time, this exact moment,
宇宙まですぐ届く高さで泳いでいる魚たち
I want to engrave it in my heart forever.
集中できてないな まだ体が迷っているんだ
Can't concentrate, my body is still hesitating.
震えていたんだじゃあ コントロールしたってブレるんだ
It was shaking; even with control, it blurs.
太陽もツキも何も完全にこっち向いていないが
Sun and luck aren't entirely on our side,
「やるしかないんだ!」言い聞かせるようにそうつぶやいた
"Just gotta do it!" I murmur to myself like a pep talk.
状況は悪いが ただ逃げ出すんじゃ根性ないな
Conditions are bad, but just running away shows no backbone.
展望はないが 度胸でクリアするしかないな
No prospects, but we've got to clear it with courage.
衝動は抑えたままターゲットとの間隔探れ
Suppressing the impulse, find the distance to the target.
必要なものは勝つプライド
What we need is a winning pride.
味わうのは勝利の美酒か
Savoring victory's sweet wine,
それとも敗北の苦汁か
or defeat's bitter dregs?
そう すべては2つに1つ
Yes, everything is two-to-one,
操りたい運命の糸を
pulling the strings of fate we want to manipulate.
絶好のゴールデンタイム この手で掴め
Grab the golden time with these hands,
渾身のポーカーフェイス キメて仕掛けるよ
put on a fierce poker face, and make your move.
イリュージョンヌの世界へ引きずり込んで
Dragging them into a world of illusion,
際限無いプレッシャーゲーム スルリと抜けて
endless pressure game, slipping right through,
栄光のボーダーライン 飛び越えるために
to leap across the borderline of glory.
ハウメニー? どれくらいの代償がいる?
How many? What's the price we pay?
ハウメニー？ どれくらいの代償がいる？
How many? What is the price to pay?
手放したくないものはどれ？
What is it that I don't want to let go of?
ロンよりショウコなんだ 要は結果を出したもんが勝者だ
Proof beats words. The winner is whoever gets results.
沈黙は金だ 口が過ぎればバレるんだ
Silence is gold. Talk too much and you'll give yourself away.
感覚を研ぎ澄まして 慎重に流れを読み切れ 現状の勝率何パーセント？
Sharpen your senses and carefully read the flow. What's our current win rate percentage?
かち割るのは堅実なゲームセンス 潜影法師は悪魔か
Slicing through it with solid game sense. Is the lurking illusionist a demon?
男ならば 潔く散ってやるくらいの覚悟で挑め
If you're a man, face it with the resolve to go down cleanly.
逆境のクラップハンズ 奮い立たせて
Clap hands in adversity, rouse your spirit!
斬新なファイティングスタイル ギリギリを攻めろ
A bold new fighting style, push it to the edge!
アテンション！危ないぜ 限界越えて
Attention! It's dangerous, breaking past our limits!
最高のフェアリーテイル 歴史に刻め 完勝の瞬間を見せつけるために
Etch the ultimate fairytale into history, to show off the moment of complete victory!
アーユーレディ？ くぐもった迷いなど捨て
Are you ready? Throw away all muffled hesitation,
バベルの階段をあがれ
and climb the stairs of Babel!
女神のように笑みを浮かべる 君の魅力に取りつかれて
Smiling like a goddess, spellbound by your charm,
誘われるまま堕ちていく
falling deeper as I'm led along.
心に住み着いた欲望 膨れ上がる果てなき夢 誰も僕をとめられない
The desire dwelling in my heart, an endless, swelling dream. No one can stop me!
絶好のゴールデンタイム この手で掴め
Grab the golden time with your own hands!
渾身のポーカーフェイス キメて仕掛けるよ
Flash your absolute poker face and make your move!
イリュージョンの世界へ 引きずり込んで
Drag them into the world of illusion,
際限無いプレッシャーゲーム スルリと抜けて
slipping smoothly through the endless pressure game.
栄光のボーダーライン 飛び越えるために
To leap across the borderline of glory!
ハウメニー？
How many?
どれくらいの代償がいる？
What is the price to pay?
逆境のクラップハンズ 奮い立たせて
Clap hands in adversity, rouse your spirit!
斬新なファイティングスタイル ギリギリを攻めろ
A bold new fighting style, push it to the edge!
アテンション！危ないぜ 限界越えて
Attention! It's dangerous, breaking past our limits!
最高のフェアリーテイル 歴史に刻め
Etch the ultimate fairytale into history,
驚愕の大逆転 華麗に決めるよ
pulling off a stunning, dazzling turnaround!
ドゥユーノウ？ 運命は奪い取るもの
Do you know? Destiny is something you seize.
バベルの頂上に差す 太陽の光を浴びろ
Bathe in the sunlight piercing the peak of Babel!
ノエル！ お誕生日 おめでとう！
Noel! Happy birthday!
お誕生日 おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
ありがとう！ ありがとう！
Thank you! Thank you!
嬉しいな！
I'm so happy!
てかさ、何この３人？
Wait, what's with this trio?
え？ シナジーなくね？
Eh? Is there zero synergy?
いや、まって。まずね、最初にクロちゃん、このステージを用意しまして...
Wait, first of all, Kuro-chan prepared this stage...
ありがとー！
Thank you!
よかったね、おめでとー！
So glad, happy birthday!
いや...
Wait...
いや、みんなわかったよね？ ちょっとリスナーさんのコメントちょっとね。
No, you guys all get it right? Let's check the listeners' comments.
え、わかった？
Eh, you get it?
わかんない！ わかんない！
I don't get it! I don't get it!
はい！正解がたくさんいますので、言うと... スロカス３姉妹！
Right! There are many correct answers, so to say... Slot-addict triplet sisters!
自分の性格... ていうか、クロちゃんぺこらと違うよね？
My personality... I mean, Kuro-chan and Pekora are different, right?
違うよね！ん？ アイと、あれ？アイでしょ？
They're different! Eh? Ai, and... wait, it's Ai right?
だってさ、ギャンブル好きだからさ、いろいろ...
Because, you know, we love gambling, so various...
スロカス！
Slot addicts!
案件とかもさ、もらったりしてさ、
Like, getting sponsored deals and stuff,
ほらね？ そうだよね？
right? Exactly.
ほら、手、覚えてる？
Look, do you remember the handshake?
勝手に身体が…
My body automatically...
動かない！ 止まらないでしょ！
Moves! You can't stop!
ちょっところねちゃん、今から打ちに行こっか！行こっか！
Hey Korone-chan, wanna go arcade gaming now? Let's go!
お疲れ様です！
Good work!
誕生会も、おうち行きたいけど、誕生日まだまだあるよー！
Even though I want an anniversary party at home, my birthday still has a long way to go!
あつまれ party people 朝まで dance dance
Gather, party people, dance until morning!
噛み嚙みだった風俗法 修正して風俗法
Mumbled business laws, corrected business laws!
暗闇で光るサングラス 車高の低さはステータス
Sunglasses glowing in the dark, low ride height is status!
流して edm dancing to the edm
Playing EDM, dancing to the EDM!
あつまれ party people 朝まで dance dance
Gather, party people, dance until morning!
噛み嚙みだった風俗法 修正して風俗法
Mumbled business laws, corrected business laws!
ショートカットで ツーブロックの 女は だいたい ダンス うまい
Girls with short hair and two-block cuts are mostly good at dancing!
party people party people
俺も混ぜてくれ 酒飲めへんけど 踊れへんけど
Let me join in too, even though I can't drink or dance!
party people party people 平日はちゃんと働いてる party people 偉い
Party people, working hard on weekdays, party people are amazing!
party people party people
俺も混ぜてくれ 酒飲めへんけど 踊れへんけど
Let me join in too, even though I can't drink or dance!
party people party people 休日 日サロで焼いてる party people
Party people, tanning on holidays, party people!
レッドブルでウォッカ割って飲んで吐いた女持ち帰って
Mixing vodka with Red Bull, drinking, taking home the girl who threw up,
朝まで楽しむ party people
enjoying until morning, party people!
party people party people
俺も混ぜてくれ 酒飲めへんけど 踊れへんけど
Let me join in too, even though I can't drink or dance!
party people party people 平日はちゃんと働いてる party people 偉い
Party people, working hard on weekdays, party people are amazing!
party people party people
俺も混ぜてくれ 酒飲めへんけど 踊れへんけど
Let me join in too, even though I can't drink or dance!
party people party people 休日 日サロで焼いてる party people
Party people, tanning on holidays, party people!
レッドブルでウォッカ割って飲んで吐いた女持ち帰って
Mixing vodka with Red Bull, drinking, taking home the girl who threw up,
朝まで楽しむ party people
enjoying until morning, party people!
party people party people
俺も混ぜてくれ 酒飲めへんけど 踊れへんけど
Let me join in too, even though I can't drink or dance!
party people party people 平日はちゃんと働いてる party people 偉い
Party people, working hard on weekdays, party people are amazing!
party people party people
俺も混ぜてくれ 酒飲めへんけど 踊れへんけど
Let me join in too, even though I can't drink or dance!
party people party people 休日 日サロで焼いてる party people
Party people, tanning on holidays, party people!
レッドブルでウォッカ割って飲んで吐いた女持ち帰って
Mixing vodka with Red Bull, drinking, taking home the girl who threw up,
朝まで楽しむ party people
enjoying until morning, party people!
いや飲んだ！いや今日は祝い事ですからね！
Man, I drank! Well, today is a celebration after all!
おめでとう！おめでとう！パーティーピーポー！
Congratulations! Congratulations! Party people!
パーティーポしたいやん。パーティーポしたいやん。
I wanna party. I wanna party.
でもさ、祝い事と言えばさ、はあ
But you know, speaking of celebrations, ah
ここにホロ酒飲み組にいますよ！新メンバー加入だよ！
Here are the Hololive drinkers! A new member has joined!
新メンバー加入で酒飲みローテーション！イェーイ！
A new member has joined the drinking rotation! Yay!
新メンバー加入だやったー！
A new member has joined, yay!
でもね、酒飲みはいましたけど、より強固な酒飲みが来たんだよ。
We already had drinkers, but an even more hardcore drinker has arrived.
ワイン担当だから！ワイン担当！
Because she's in charge of wine! Wine charge!
いや、振ってたよ！振っちゃいけない。
No, she was shaking it! You mustn't shake it.
乾杯しよう 乾杯!
Let's do a toast, a toast!
今日だっからそんな楽しくてさ
Today is so fun and...
あ、みんな写真撮っ…あ、ハッシュタグでね!
Ah, everyone take pictures... Ah, with the hashtag!
ほら、乾杯ね! 乾杯! 乾杯! 乾杯!
Look, a toast! Toast! Toast! Toast!
いや満足だの。くしくしょ。あれ、ハッシュタグでね! いっぱいスクショしてください。
Man, I'm satisfied. Damn. Um, with the hashtag! Please take lots of screenshots.
ほら、ほら酒飲み巡りと
Look, look, the bar-hopping tour and...
あと今日のハッシュタグは？ 今日日のハッシュタグはここに書いてあります!
And what's today's hashtag? Today's hashtag is written right here!
です! よろしくお願いします!
It is! Please look forward to it!
あと美味しいお酒いっぱい飲ませてください! がんがんがん! あとポーションもよろしくね。
And please let me drink lots of delicious alcohol! Gan-gan! And please look forward to the potions too.
じゃあこの辺で次行きましょうか。
Well, shall we move on to the next part around here?
いや、そうだね。
Yeah, that's right.
あり、あり！
Yes, yes!
え、ちょっとまだある？ じゃあがんばって！
Eh, is there still more? Well, do your best!
ちょっと待って！いや、いや、いや、いや。
Wait a minute! No, no, no, no.
夜中もうすぐ
Midnight is coming soon.
しゃ、しゃ、しゃ、しゃ、しゃ、しゃ！
Sha, sha, sha, sha!
しゃ、しゃ、しゃ、しゃ、しゃ、しゃ、しゃ、しゃ！
レディーパーティー！
Ready Party!
リンリン・ドンドン この音がビビキッタ イモヒタ 感じて
Ring-ring, dong-dong, this sound just vibrated right now, feeling it deep inside.
リリカル Monster
Lyrical Monster
ジャーヤ・ホィ・モット・エンジョイ！ リリカル・フィーリング！
Joy, yeah, hoy, more enjoy! Lyrical feeling!
ジョージョー・キブンも、チューツヨ・ホームラン！
High spirits too, full strength home run!
男女・オシの才能、ヒエラルキーはウィー・セッテ・アゲル！
Men and women, push's talent, the hierarchy is... I'll show you!
ラブリー・パーティー！
Lovely party!
キュル・キュル・キル・ルン・ルン、巻き起こるコドモのタイフーンへ
Kyuru-kyuru-kir-run-run, heading towards the rising children's typhoon,
もっとハッピー！とことん・とことん、届けちゃうよ！
even happier! Thoroughly, thoroughly delivering it to you!
ソーダろう？こんなろう？ときめき・タロウ！ラ・ラ・ラ・ライフは・パワフル・デス・カー？
Isn't that so? Like this? Throbbing, Tarou! La-la-la-life is powerful?
ちょっとウィ・ウィット、感じたら止めらんない、止められないくらい胸のドキドキ・ドキ
If you feel a little 'wi-wit', you can't stop it, you can't stop it, my heart goes doki-doki.
ドキ！一周回って、現在・シン・コク、グルー・グルー、追いかけて、コ・アラ・ラ・ラ・アラモード！
Doki! Going around once, currently deep-seated, goo-goo, chasing after, ko-a-la-la-la-a la mode!
リン・リン・ドン・ドン、この音がビビキッタ、イモヒタ、もっと感じて！
Ring-ring, dong-dong, this sound vibrated right now, felt even more, feeling it even more!
ジャンプン・ジャンプン、ディス・プレイス、オ・ジャンミ・オー・サンポ、キープ！新世代・ライト、イロ・ハロウィン、認めません！
Jumpin' jumpin' this place, o-janmi-o-sampo, keep! New generation light, iro-halloween, I won't accept it!
史上・最高のことば、マ・イ・サ・イ・ユ・ウ・アイ・アイ、ここを語れり！
History's greatest words, ma-i-sa-i-yu-u-ai-ai, talk about this here!
ずっと見ててね、デカリ・モ・サ・キ・ア・イ！
Keep watching me forever, deka-ri-mo-sa-ki-a-i!
ライメリー・ゴラ・キャリー・ゴラ・レディ・ゴラ、夢のようなステージでエスコート！
Rainy-merry-go-round, candy-go-round, ready-go-round, escort me on a dream-like stage!
時の流れはいつでもゆっくり
The flow of time is always slow
だけどハートの動くスピードひらぐれば愛
But the speed at which the heart moves, if you open it, is love.
聞かせたよ、この場所へちゃんと届くように
Let me hear it, so that it reaches this place properly.
キミのクラップ・クラップ・クラップ、エディ・バーリ・クラップ・ハン・アップ・サレダラ
Your clap, clap, clap, eddy barry clap, if you are embraced...
ルン・ライ・メリー・ゴラ・キャリー・ゴラ・レディ・ゴラ、夢のようなスピードで飛び出そう
Run, lie, merry-go-round, candy-go-round, ready-go-round, let's fly out at a dream-like speed.
歌に飛び込めば行けるんだ
If you dive into the song, you can go anywhere.
タイムスリップも止められない
Time slip cannot be stopped either.
ライフ・メリー・ゴラ・キャリー・ゴラ、出会えるは始まりの
Life, merry-go-round, candy-go-round, our encounter is the beginning
ベルが鳴り響く夜に
on the night the bell rings out.
向こうに行こう！同じリズム、一つのナンバー、奏でよう！
Let's go beyond! Play the same rhythm, the same number!
気づいてるんでしょ、ここにいる意味さえも
You've noticed, haven't you, even the meaning of being here.
切り札はそれぞれ、高いの手札に
Our trumps are each in our high hands.
頭と心で暴き出して胸を撃ち抜け！
Expose it with your head and heart, and shoot through your chest!
自覚ないんでしょ、ねえ、思い通りに、キミは動かされていること
You aren't aware of it, right? That you are being moved just as you wish.
単純じゃないの、駆け引きのヒントを
It's not simple, all the hints of negotiation
全て拾って、いつもの冗談でにすることで
gathering them all, and turning them into your usual joke
理解できた愛の形をどこかの誰かに仕留められても
even if the form of love you understood is shot down by someone somewhere,
最後に笑うキミと
with you, who laughs at the end,
家族していく
let's walk together / keep going...
でいり〜だあいり〜！
Deiri~ Daiari~!
届けちゃおう
Let's deliver it!
せーしゅん実況中！
Live-stream broadcasting!
（いろいろ）
(Various things)
ちょーせーん配信中！
Challenge streaming!
（試して）
(Give it a try)
せーしゅん実況中！
Live-stream broadcasting!
（いっぱい）
(All out)
ちょーせーん配信中！
Challenge streaming!
（遊ぼう）
(Let's play)
ほらね 楽しいを発見！
Look, I found fun!
また新しい「好き」が見つかったよ
I found a new "like" again!
（何々？超気になる）
(What's that? So curious!)
近所にできたカフェの「ケーキ」
A "cake" at a nearby café
なんかすごく美味しかったんだよ
It was really delicious!
（食レポになってないで）
(That's not a food review!)
知らなかったゲームや（新作！）
Games I didn't know (New release!)
聞いたことない歌（新曲！）
Songs I've never heard (New song!)
ちょっと気になったら手を出しちゃう
If I'm curious, I'll dive right in!
ほ・ら・ま・た いっしょに遊ぼう！（配信！）
Look, let's play together again! (Stream!)
10連ガチャ引いてみよう（爆死！）
Let's roll a 10-pull gacha (Epic fail!)
ホラーゲームやってみよう（絶叫！）
Let's play a horror game (Screaming!)
あの曲歌ってみよう（感動！）
Let's sing that song (Moving!)
ぜんぶがもう楽しいの！
Everything is just so fun!
窓の向こうの笑顔に手を振っちゃう
Wave to the smile on the other side of the window!
せーしゅん実況中！
Live-stream broadcasting!
（いろいろ）
(Various things)
ちょーせーん配信中！
Challenge streaming!
（試して）
(Give it a try)
せーしゅん実況中！
Live-stream broadcasting!
（いっぱい）
(All out)
ちょーせーん配信中！
Challenge streaming!
（遊ぼう）
(Let's play)
でいり〜だあいり〜！
Deiri~ Daiari~!
届けよう！
Let's deliver it!
せーしゅん実況中！
Live-stream broadcasting!
（いろいろ）
(Various things)
ちょーせーん配信中！
Challenge streaming!
（試して）
(Give it a try)
せーしゅん実況中！
Live-stream broadcasting!
（いっぱい）
(All out)
ちょーせーん配信中！
Challenge streaming!
（遊ぼう）
(Let's play)
でいり〜だあいり〜！
Deiri~ Daiari~!
届けよう！
Let's deliver it!
ノエル！
Noel!
お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
よっしゃー、ありがとう！
Yay, thank you!
4回目もやれて嬉しいよ！
I'm so happy to do this for the 4th time!
今年もあっという間だったね！
This year went by so fast, didn't it!
今年も大変お世話になりました！来年もよろしく！
Thank you so much for everything this year! Please treat me well next year too!
え、待って。いや、それ2回目...
Wait. No, that's the second...
ちょっと待って！待って待って
Wait a minute! Wait, wait!
しかも、し・ご・う・ぴー！
And Shi-go-u-pi!
いや、みんな動きおかしかったからね！
No, everyone's movements were weird!
自分ってこんな動きしてたんだっけ？気持ち悪いよ
Was I moving like that? That's creepy!
ちょっと、おかしいって！あなたの動きだからこれ！
Hey, that's weird! That's your movement!
自分ってこんな動きしてたんだっけ？気持ち悪いよ
Did I really move like that? That's creepy!
そうだね！めっっちゃいじってるじゃん
That's right! You're teasing so much!
いやでも本当にみんな来てくれてありがとう！
But seriously, thank you everyone for coming!
このメンバーでなんで呼ばれたか分かりますか？
Do you know why this member was called?
想像つくかな？ なんでだろ？
Can you imagine? Why is that?
今日はハッピーライブということで、本当にその、一緒に歌いたい、好きな人を集めたんですけど
Today is a happy live, so I gathered people I really want to sing with, people I like, but
え？好きってこと？
Huh? You like them?
え？好きってこと？え、好きってこと？
Huh? You like them? Huh, you like them?
いや、好きだけど！好きだけどね！
No, I like them! I like them, of course!
もっと！もっと！好きだよ！
More! More! I love you!
そうなんです。しかもメドレーにしたらさ、すごい面白いかなと思ってメドレーやったんですよ
That's right. Plus, I thought it would be really fun if we did a medley, so we did a medley!
楽しかった！楽しかった！
It was fun! It was fun!
この5人でちょっと写真撮って結構アッカンじゃないですか？
Taking a picture with these 5 people is pretty amazing, right?
確かに！なんか横にでかいハムスターいるよ
True! There's a huge hamster next to us!
ハムちゃん、大賛成じゃん
Ham-chan is all for it!
うずらんなくて。あ、じゃあこっちのハムスターと一緒に
It's irresistible. Ah, then together with this hamster here!
イェーイ！イェーイ！
Yay! Yay!
こっちのラインさんも寂しいて言ってる
The Line-san over here says they're lonely too!
アンチスキー行きましょう！せーの、イェーイ！
Let's go anti-ski! Ready, yay!
いや満足！ありがとうみんな、イェーイ！
Satisfied! Thank you everyone, yay!
まだまだライブ続くんで、皆さん頑張りましょう！
The live continues, let's all do our best!
皆さん良いお年を！
Everyone, have a good year!
来年も幸せになりますように！良い年を！
May next year be happy! Have a good year!
ありがとうございました！来年も頑張る！
Thank you very much! I'll do my best next year too!
消える飛行機雲
The fading vapor trails
僕たちは見送った
We watched them go
消える飛行機雲 僕たちは見送った
We watched the fading vapor trail disappear,
眩しくて逃げた いつだって弱くて
Too dazzled to stay, we always ran away.
あの日から変わらず いつまでも変わらずに
Ever since that day, unchanging, forever the same,
いられなかったこと 悔しくて指を離す
Regretting what we couldn't be, we let go of our fingers.
あの鳥はまだうまく飛べないけれど
That bird can't fly very well yet,
いつかは風を切って知る
Someday it will cut through the wind and know.
届かない場所がまだ遠くにある
The place it cannot reach is still far away,
願いだけ秘めて見つめている
Hiding only its wish, it gazes on.
子供たちは夏の線路歩く
The children walk along the summer railway tracks,
吹く風に素足をさらして
Exposing their bare feet to the blowing wind.
遠くには幼かった日々を
Far away are those days of our youth,
両手には飛び立つ希望を
With hope ready to take flight in both hands.
消える飛行機雲 追いかけて追いかけて
Chasing and chasing the fading vapor trail,
あの丘を越えた あの日から変わらず
Since we crossed over this hill that day,
いつまでもまっすぐに僕たちはあるように
We've always walked straight ahead.
わたづみのような強さを守れるよきっと
Protecting a strength like cotton fluff.
あの空を回る 風車の羽根たちは
The windmill blades turning in that sky
いつも同じ夢見る
Always dream the same dream,
届かない場所をずっと見つめている
Gazing endlessly at the place they cannot reach,
願いを秘めた鳥の夢を
Dreaming a bird's dream, holding their wish.
振り返る 灼けた線路覆う 入道雲
Looking back at the thunderclouds covering the scorched tracks,
形を変えても僕らは覚えていて
Even as they change shape, we remember them.
どうか季節が残した昨日を
May the seasons of yesterday linger on.
消える飛行機雲 追いかけて追いかけて
Chasing and chasing the fading vapor trail,
早すぎる合図 ふたり笑い出してる
It was an early sign, and we both smiled.
いつまでもまっすぐに眼差はあるように
Always striving to look straight ahead,
汗がにじんでも手を離さないよずっと
Even if we sweat, we will never let go of our hands.
消える飛行機雲 僕たちは見送った
We watched the fading vapor trail disappear,
眩しくて逃げた いつだって弱くて
Too dazzled to stay, we always ran away.
あの日から変わらず いつまでも変わらずに
Ever since that day, unchanging, forever the same,
いられなかったこと 悔しくて指を離す
Regretting what we couldn't be, we let go of our fingers.
あの鳥はまだうまく飛べないけれど
That bird can't fly very well yet,
いつかは風を切って知る
Someday it will cut through the wind and know.
届かない場所がまだ遠くにある
The place it cannot reach is still far away,
願いだけ秘めて見つめている
Hiding only its wish, it gazes on.
子供たちは夏の線路歩く
The children walk along the summer railway tracks,
吹く風に素足をさらして
Exposing their bare feet to the blowing wind.
はーい！鳥の歌でした！
Hi! That was "Song of the Bird"!
すごい！なんか羽ばたいてく感じ
Amazing! It feels like spreading my wings.
大空に鳥に羽ばた...あ、ちょっと待て
Spreading my wings like a bird in the sky... Ah, wait a minute.
なんか...団長、あれが歌いたくなってきた！
Somehow... Danchou, I feel like singing that song!
どん！歌います！
Boom! Let's sing!
ギラギラの太陽がある ワクワクが待ちきれない
With a glaring sun, I can't wait for the excitement.
あれもしたい これもしたい Let's Summer time!
I want to do that, I want to do this, Let's Summer time!
青い空と白い雲が
The blue sky and white clouds
心のボルテージ上げていく
lift up the voltage in my heart.
ラムネ色のTシャツはね
My ramune-colored T-shirt
今年いちばんのレモネード
is this year's best lemonade.
走り出した海岸線
Running out along the coastline,
どこまでだって行けそうだね
it feels like we can go anywhere.
数えきれない夏休みチャレンジ
Countless summer vacation challenges—
キミも一緒にいこ！
let's go together!
あっという間に進んでく時計
The clock ticks by in the blink of an eye.
短すぎじゃない？ My Summer time!
Isn't it too short? My Summer time!
全部最高の思い出にするの追い風
A tailwind turns everything into the best memories.
みんな連れてけ！
Take everyone along!
素晴らしい太陽がサンサン
The wonderful sun is shining brightly,
せのでJUMP！弾ける汗
Ready, set, JUMP! Sweat flying everywhere.
宝石みたいにキラキラ
Sparkling like jewels,
眩しく輝け！
shine dazzlingly!
ギラギラの太陽がある ドキドキがいっぱいです
With a glaring sun, my heart is full of excitement.
あれもしよう これもやろう Let's Summer time!
Let's do that, let's try this, Let's Summer time!
涼しい風寝転がって
Laying down in the cool breeze,
伸び伸びってお昼寝しよう
let's take a nice, stretching nap.
夢の仲間は何だって出来ちゃう
With dream companions, we can do anything.
キラキラ光を飛ばした
We sent sparkling light flying.
流れ星を見つけにいこう
Let's go find shooting stars.
夜更かしだってへっちゃらだよ
Staying up late is no problem at all!
願いごとは溢れそうな時は
When my wishes are overflowing,
ミルキーウェイダイビング
it's Milky Way diving.
ちょっとくらいヘタッても平気
It's fine even if I stumble a bit.
みんながくれるファイトがある
I have the fighting spirit everyone gives me.
どこまでだって駆け抜けてゆけからいいよね
Running through to the end is just fine, right?
準備はOK？
Are you ready?
のえる！あたしにきたぞ！
Noel! It's my turn!
ひとつひとつが全部全部が
Every single thing, all of it,
届いているから上を向いて
is reaching me, so look up high.
体中に息を吸い込んだなら叫ぶよ
If you take a deep breath in your body, shout out:
みんな大好き！
We love everyone so much!
のえるおめでとう！
Happy birthday, Noel!
毎日が記念日になれー
May every day become an anniversary!
キミのココロ照らしちゃおう
Let's light up your heart.
新しい元気をまるっとお届けしちゃうよ
We'll deliver brand-new energy all in one go!
空のかなたまで飛んでこう
Let's fly away to the far side of the sky.
せのでJUMP！弾ける汗
Ready, set, JUMP! Sweat flying everywhere.
宝石みたいにキラキラ
Sparkling like jewels,
眩しく輝け！
shine dazzlingly!
ギラギラの太陽がある 欲張っていっちゃいます
With a glaring sun, let's be greedy!
あれもしたい これもしたい Let's Summer time!
I want to do that, I want to do this, Let's Summer time!
のえるおめでとうー！
Happy birthday, Noel!
どうしてなのえる！それでは...恥ずかしながらあの太陽少女を歌った...
Why, Noel? And so... feeling a bit shy, we sang "Taiyou Shoujo"...
のえるが違うからよ！
Because Noel is different!
のえる本当に、おめでとう！すごい！ダンスすごかったよ歌も！
Noel, truly, happy birthday! Amazing! Your dance and vocals were amazing!
団長ずっと、あれな、去年のすば先輩のライブを見てからどうしても夢があって...あの団長そのすば先輩の歌をあの...踊って歌ってよ頑張りたいの！
Danchou has always had this dream ever since watching Subaru-senpai's live last year... Danchou wanted to dance and sing Subaru-senpai's song and do her best!
終わってたんです！
It's already over!
ありがと、ノエルうれしい。ほんと、めちゃめちゃよかった！
Thank you, Noel, I'm so happy. Seriously, it was amazing!
うにゃん！
Unyan!
うれしい。あっ、ありがとうございます。
I'm so happy. Thank you so much.
あっ、大丈夫？
Are you okay?
あっ、大丈夫？なんか、ダンスしてる時よりも、ちょっと心拍数が……。
Are you okay? Your heart rate's higher than when you were dancing!
やばい。今ね、いいよ、いいよ。
Right now?
なん、なんだよ、なんだよ、おかしいよ。ダンスの時とかやばいな、絶対。
No, seriously, your heart rate during the dance must be crazy!
ちょっとね、これからもね、よかったら仲良くしてね。
Let's get along even better from now on too!
お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
ありがと！いえーい！いえーい！ありがと！
Yay! Yay! Thank you!
ありがとうございます。あっ、そうだ、船長、船長。
Thank you so much, Senpai.
何？
What?
じゃ、じゃ、写真撮りますか？
Can we take a picture?
あっ、撮るか！撮ろっ。
Ah, let's take one!
何する？
What should we do?
えっ、団長、やっぱ船長先輩って今日、歌って踊ったんで、歌って踊ったから、うん、そっか。
Well, Senpai, since we sang and danced today...
歌って踊ったから、うん。
You danced and sang!
なんか好きな振り付けがあって、やっぱあれなんですよ、ここ。
You have your favorite choreography, right?
あっ、これね！これ！そうそうそう。だから。
Ah, this one! This one!
あっ、ほら、みんな、だんじょうたって、ほら、一緒にほら、おどろ、おどろ、おどろっ！
Look, everyone! Let's do the birthday dance together!
ノエル、おめでと！
Happy birthday to Noel!
あっ、やっ、あっ！
Ah, yay!
だって、距離が近いてたあれじゃん。
Wait, we were right next to each other, weren't we?
あっ、そうだよね。えっ、じゃあそうだよね。
Ah, that's right!
そうそう、そうそう。いや、はっぴーです。今日、あれ、はっぴーって書いてあるんで、
So yeah, it's "Happy"!
いや、まだまだ、実ははっぴーなことがあってですね。
Actually, there's a "Happy" occasion!
そうなの？
Really?
そうなんです。あっ、ちょっと団長もその準備があるので、一緒にいきますか？じゃあ、一緒に、はっぴーしに行こう！
And Captain, you have preparations for that too, so shall we go together?
一緒に！
Together!
はっぴーしに行こう！一緒に、はっぴーしに！一緒に、いこ、いこ、いこ！ねえ！
Let's go, let's go!
楽しかったー！
That was so much fun!
いや、めちゃめちゃ、はっぴーなライブだったんじゃないでしょうか。
Wasn't this a super happy live?
いや、最後、いや、最後マジで心臓が止まるかと思ったんですけど、
I thought my heart was going to stop at the very end.
いや、完全にね、団長得くなライブでしたけど、
It was totally a captain-style live, but...
いやー、これはね、団長が誕生日だから、はっぴーに過ごそうっていうね、だけじゃないんです。
Yeah, this is because it's the Captain's birthday, so we should make it super happy!
えっ、ちょっと画面のみんなびっくりしてると思うんですけど、本当ね、なんでハッピーだったかちょっと今、言います！
Wait, I bet everyone watching is surprised, but let me tell you why it was "Happy"!
ドルドルドルドルドルドル、ドゥン！
Ta-da!
なんと、この後、団長オリジナル曲出しまーす！イエーイ！そして、お披露目もしちゃいます！
And we'll also be revealing it!
ということでね、あの、そのオリジナル曲のタイトルが「はっぴー」ということで、ひらがなでね、「はっぴー」なんですょ。
So, the title of that original song is "Happy"—in hiragana, "はっぴー"!
で、しかもその曲を作ってくださった方が、あの有名なDECO*27さんということでね、団長もついにDECO*27さんに作ってもらえるようになりました！
And moreover, the person who made that song is the famous DECO*27-san, so the Captain finally got to have DECO*27-san make a song for her!
そりゃね、第3さんの日々の応援のおかげです。ありがとうございます！
That's all thanks to everyone's daily support! Thank you so much!
ということで、一応ね、お披露目した後に、あの24時から、あとリリースもされますので、そちらもよろしくお願いします。
So, basically, right after the reveal, starting at 24:00, the release will also happen, so please check that out too!
あとね、あの、定番なんですが、生誕グッズも発売いたします！
And also, as a staple, birthday goods will also be released!
それはね、オリジナル曲の後に発表しますので、なにとぞよろしくお願いします。いやー、どんなグッズなんだろうな。ドゥンが来るのかな？いや、楽しみなんですけど、最後まで見ててくれると嬉しいです。
It will be announced after the original song, so please look forward to it, I'd be so happy if you watch until the end!
そのあと、ちなみにね、生誕グッズはね、数量限定なので、はい、あの、欲しい人は、あの直筆、あっ、生誕グッズ、数量限定じゃねえ、あ、あ、あの、数量限定じゃないよ。
Oh, and by the way, the birthday goods are quantity-limited, so...
直筆が数量限定なので、なにとぞ、直筆サインが欲しい人は、あの、張り付いてね、頑張ってください！
Directly signed items are quantity-limited, so if you want a direct-signed version, please make sure to grab yours!
そしてね、メンバー限定に、あのグリーンバック素材とかもあります。
And for member-limited items, we also have green-back materials!
このね、アイドルショーだったりとかのグリーンバック素材もあるので、そちらも要チェック！メンバーさんよろしくね！
Like the idol show or green-back materials, so please check those out too, Member-san, please look forward to it!
ということで、あっ、時間ない！着替えてきまーす！およよよよよよ！
So, I'm going to go change now! See you later!
もうハイになっちゃうよ ねぇ、おっけー？
Even high, it's getting high, you know, okay?
受け取ってよ ねぇ、おっけー？
Accept it, you know, okay?
きみのことが好き だもん
Because I love you so much!
いい感じって勘違いしちゃって
It feels so good, but I might have misunderstood...
恥ずかしくなっちゃうじゃん ばか ばか
Making it embarrassing, right? Dummy, dummy!
あー 待って それ以上 私に近づかないで
Ah, wait, don't get any closer to me than that!
caution caution 押し込んだ感情が 脱走 脱走
Caution, caution! Overwhelming feelings are running wild!
想いのドミノ 倒してみて 止まらなくて困るかも
Knock over the dominoes of my thoughts, it might get out of hand!
言いたいこと全部言えちゃう魔法を とけちゃうくらいの砂糖を たっぷりかけて
Pour on enough sugar to make you melt away all the things you wanted to say!
それではっぴーじゃん きみが笑うなら それがはっぴーじゃん
So it's happy if you smile, that's what happy is!
心スキップしてジャンプして 落ち込んでだめだめだって
Heart skipping and jumping, don't say it's hopeless when you're feeling down,
一回のきみの笑顔で 全部忘れちゃうから
One smile from you makes me forget all about it!
もうなにをやったってはい おっけー 謝ったらはい おっけー
No matter what I did, it's fine, okay? If I made a mistake, it's fine, okay?
甘え過ぎたら「めっ！」ってしといてね
If I get too spoiled, tell me off with a "Hey!"
もうハイになっちゃうよ ねぇ おっけー？ きみのことが好き だもん
Even high, it's getting high, you know, okay? Because I love you so much!
伝えたい言葉が
The words I want to tell you,
溢れ出す気持ちが
The overflowing feelings,
きみを目指して
Aiming for you,
また大渋滞して
Causing another traffic jam.
鳴り響くクラクション
Claxons are blaring,
思いきっちゃえば楽勝？
If I just go for it, is it a breeze?
踏み込んでしまうのは いつもブレーキなんだよ
Stepping on it is always hitting the brakes.
想いのオセロ 返してみて
Try flipping the othello of feelings,
挟まれたら染まるかも
If I get sandwiched, maybe I'll turn your color.
言いたいこと全部言えちゃう魔法で
With magic to say everything I want to say,
とろけちゃうくらいの砂糖で ドキドキさせたい
I want to make your heart race with enough sugar to melt.
でもあはっぴーじゃん 見てくなくちゃ
But hey, it's happy, if you don't look at me,
またあはっぴーじゃん 心フリックしてショートして
Again it's happy, heart flicking and short-circuiting.
落ち込んでだめだめだって
Saying "I'm depressed, no good, no good,"
一回のきみの笑顔で 全部忘れちゃうけど
Just one smile from you makes me forget it all,
それもはっぴーじゃん きみといられたら つまりはっぴーじゃん
That's also happy! If I'm with you, in short, it's happy!
心スキップしてジャンプして
Skipping and jumping in my heart,
落ち込んでだめだめだって
Saying "I'm depressed, no good, no good,"
一回のきみの笑顔で 全部忘れちゃうから
Because just one smile from you makes me forget it all.
もうなにをやったって はい、おっけー
Whatever I did, yeah, okay!
謝ったら はい、おっけー
If I apologized, yeah, okay!
甘え過ぎたら 増やしといてね
If I acted too spoiled, keep it in mind!
もうハイになんちゃいよね、おっけー 受け取ってよね、おっけー
I'm getting high now, okay? Receive it, okay?
きみのことが好きなんだよ
I love you so much!
もう何があったって はい、おっけー
No matter what happened, yeah, okay!
泣いちゃっても はい、おっけー
Even if I cry, yeah, okay!
大好きのバフ きっと続いてく
The buff of love will surely keep going.
もうハイになんちゃいよね、おっけー 受け取ってよね、おっけー
I'm getting high now, okay? Receive it, okay?
きみのことが好きすぎて 私はっぴーだもん
I love you so much, I'm just so happy!
第3弾、まだまだお知らせがあります！
Part 3, we still have more announcements!
今年もノエルちゃん誕生日記念グッズ、販売いたします！イェーイ！ぱふぱふぱふぱふ！
This year's Shirogane Noel Birthday Commemorative Goods will go on sale! Yay!
てことで時間が無いのでね、さっそく紹介なんですが、今年はね4種類のグッズを出します。
So since we don't have much time, let's get right into the introductions.
まず1つ目がバスタオル。
First up is the bath towel.
これはノエルちゃん、なんかちょっと、なんかバスタ、エ、エ、エな感じなんですけど、ま、バスタオル姿でね、あの、団員さんの分の牛丼を作って、あの、おかえりなさいをしてる、とても不思議なバスタオルになっております。
This bath towel... Noel-chan looks kind of ecchi, but in her bath towel outfit, she's making a gyudon bowl for the danin-san and welcoming them home. It's a very mysterious bath towel!
そして、2つ目が白銀愛好会どんぶり2022年バージョンということで、
And second is the Shirogane Fan Club Donburi 2022 version,
以前ね、どんぶり出したことあるんですけど、こちらはより、あの、白銀ノエルのオリジナルデザインに近い、あの、牛丼のどんぶりとなっております。あの、そこにね、なんかメッセージがあるみたいなので、ちょっとお楽しみにと いうことでね。
We've released a donburi before, but this one is even closer to Shirogane Noel's original gyudon donburi design. There's apparently a message on the bottom, so look forward to that!
で、えっと3つ目が団員手帳です。ま、団員さん、白銀聖騎士団専用の、あの、団員手帳となっているので、ぜひぜひここにメモをいっぱい書いてください。
And third is the Danin Notebook. Since it's an official notebook dedicated to the Shirogane Holy Knights, please write lots of notes in here!
で、えっと4つ目最後が団長とお揃いジョッキ。これはお揃っちなのでぜひぜひこれでね、あの、お酒を飲んでください。
And fourth, lastly, is the matching stein with the Dancho. This is a matching set, so please enjoy your drinks with this!
で、フルセットの特典なんですけど、ま、ポストカード、あの白銀ノエルメッセージが書いていますので、ぜひぜひ数量限定バージョンはね、あの、直筆サインがありますので、何卒よろしくお願いします。特定ASMRボイスはね、あの、数量限定、限定じゃないどちらにもあるので、よろしくお願いします。
And for the full set bonus, there's a postcard with a handwritten message from Shirogane Noel for the limited quantity version. The special ASMR voice is included in both versions, so thank you!
はい、時間がオーバーしました！
Okay, we're out of time!
では、バイバイ！みんな買ってね！団長もっともっとはっぴーになっちゃいます、みんなが買ってくれると。ぜひぜひ買ってくださーい！バイバーイ！
Well then, bye-bye! Everyone buy it! Dancho will become even happier if you all buy it. Please buy it! Bye-bye!